A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections, Grant Funded Materials FA1839
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant File Attachments - Publications and Reports, 1955-2018; 5; 23.46 Cubic Feet
  - Creative Capital Foundation PA 10301353 - 2005 Grantee Handbook (Box 34, Folder 199)
    Grant Purpose: For grants and technical assistance to individual artists working in diverse media who are pursuing innovation in form and/or content
    Grant Amount: $1,200,000.00; $1,200,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Uno, Roberta
  - Women's Learning Partnerships PA 10101227, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 200)
    Grant Dates: 10101227
    Grant Number: 2001 May 01-2011 June 30
  - Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development PA 10000393, 1999-2003 (Box 35, Folder 201-203)
    Grant Dates: 2000 February 01-2010 June 30
    Grant Number: 10000393
    Grant Purpose: Support for Honoring Nations, an awards program that identifies, celebrates, and shares information about outstanding examples of American Indian tribal governance
    Grant Amount: $5,542,641.00; $5,542,641.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Lipsky, Michael; Edwards, Michael; McFate, Katherine
  - President and Fellows of Harvard College PA 09901022 - Harvard Trade Union Program Summit and Conference Publications, 1999-2004 (Box 36, Folder 204-206, Box 37, Folder 207-210)
  - Third World Network PA 10300791, 2004-2005 (Box 38, Folder 211)
    Grantee: Third World Network Berhad
    Grant Dates: 2003 March 01-2011 December 31
    Grant Number: 10300791
    Grant Purpose: For strategic workshops and meetings among Asian government officials, academics and civil society groups on the governance of the World Trade Organization
    Grant Amount: $1,550,000.00; $1,550,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Montes, Manuel F.; Burlamaqui, Leonardo
  - The Black AIDS Institute PA 10451335 - Articles and Retreat, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 212)
    Grantee: African American AIDS Policy and Training Institute
    Grant Dates: 2004 September 01-2008 August 31
    Grant Number: 10451335
    Grant Purpose: To build a network of trained black, gay HIV/AIDS advocates and reduce HIV health disparities based upon racial and ethnic factors
    Grant Amount: $443,000.00; $443,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Winters, David; McGovern, Terry; Harris, Loren
  - Institute on Taxation and Economic Policy PA 09801636 - Arkansas Report, 2003 (Box 38, Folder 213)
    Grantee: Institute on Taxation and Economic Policy
    Grant Dates: 1998 September 01-2012 December 31
    Grant Number: 09801636
    Grant Purpose: Support to bring up-to-date and maintain itep's tax policy model
    Ford Program Officer(s): Lipsky, Michael; McFate, Katherine
  - Southern Organizing Cooperative PA 10301392, 2003-2005 (Box 38, Folder 214)
    Grantee: Southern Organizing Cooperative
    Grant Dates: 2004 January 01-2005 December 31
    Grant Number: 10301392
    Grant Purpose: General support to promote and bolster community organizing efforts
    Ford Program Officer(s): Vaid, Urvashi
  - Rural Equity Coalition PA 10200998, 2003-2004 (Box 38, Folder 215)
    Grantee: Rural School and Community Trust
    Grant Dates: 2002 May 01-2008 July 31
    Grant Number: 10200998
    Grant Purpose: Core support for the Rural Equity Collaborative to improve the adequacy and equity of school finance systems and for a national convening on school finance reform
    Grant Amount: $3,730,800.00; $3,730,800.00
  - Philippine Legislators' Committee on Population and Development Foundation PA 10000328 - Advocacy Alert, 12th Congress Terminal Report, Summary and Status of Selected Legislative Measures in Congress, 2003 July-2004 June (Box 38, Folder 216)
    Grantee: Philippine Legislators' Committee on Population and Development Foundation, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 2000 January 01-2005 December 31
    Grant Number: 10000328
    Grant Purpose: Support to raise public awareness of gender and reproductive health legislation by involving legislators as public educators in a national campaign using various media and communication tools
  - International Rescue Committee Inc. PA 09701228 - Women's Commission for Refugee Women and Children, 1997-2004 (Box 38, Folder 217)
    Grantee: International Rescue Committee
    Grant Dates: 1997 July 01-2009 October 31
    Grant Number: 09701228
    Grant Purpose: Support for work of the women's commission for refugee women and children to enhance protection and participation of refugee women
    Grant Amount: $1,160,000.00; $1,160,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Higashi, Taryn; TBS - Migrant and Refugee Rights
  - Princeton University PA 10001749, 2003-2004 (Box 38, Folder 218)
    Grantee: Princeton University
    Grant Dates: 2000 September 01-2009 December 31
    Grant Number: 10001749
    Grant Purpose: Support for the pilot phase of a reseaerch project to assess the consequences of changed admission policies on minority college enrollment in the state of texas
    Grant Amount: $2,720,000.00; $2,720,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Balan, Jorge; Anderson, Gregory (Gregory Mark)
  - National Council for Research on Women PA 09700130, 1997-2004 (Box 39, Folder 219-220)
    Grant Number: 09700130
  - California State University Sacramento Foundation PA 10000691 - Race and Democracy in the Americas, 2000-2002 (Box 39, Folder 221)
    Grantee: California State University Sacramento Foundation
    Grant Dates: 2000 March 01-2005 January 31
    Grant Number: 10000691
    Grant Purpose: Support for two workshops on race, politics, and higher education in Brazil and the United States
    Grant Amount: $467,000.00; $467,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Balan, Jorge; Fraser, Gertrude Jacinta
  - Wider Opportunities for Women PA 09700597 - State Organizing Project for Self-Sufficiency, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 222)
    Grantee: Wider Opportunities for Women
    Grant Dates: 1996 November 01-2011 April 30
    Grant Number: 09700597
    Grant Purpose: Support for the state organizing family self-sufficiency project for community-based organizations focusing on anti-poverty policy (960-1148)
    Grant Amount: $4,240,000.00; $4,240,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Neuborne, Helen; Sconyers, Nancy; Colborn, John L.; Manus, Mara A.; Lipsky, Michael; McGahey, Richard; TBS - Development Finance; Cordero-Guzman, Hector R.
  - Project Grad USA PA 10300145 - New Site Development Handbook, 2005 (Box 40, Folder 223)
    Grantee: Project Grad USA
    Grant Dates: 2002 November 01-2007 September 30
    Grant Number: 10300145
    Grant Purpose: To strengthen its capacity to provide technical assistance to all GRAD sites
    Grant Amount: $14,875,000.00; $14,875,000.00
  - UCLA - Center for African American Studies (CAAS) PA 10201940 - Enhancing Higher Education Access and Achievement Among African American Students: A Research and Programmatic Effort, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 224)
    Grantee: The Regents of the University of California, Los Angeles
    Grant Dates: 2002 October 01-2007 September 30
    Grant Number: 10201940
    Grant Purpose: For the Center for African American Studies to strengthen scholarship and increase public awareness of Proposition 209's impact on African-American access to higher education in California
    Grant Amount: $700,000.00; $700,000.00
  - The Aspen Institute, Inc PA 09700745 - Crafting the Message: Effective Communications Strategies for Sector Practitioners, National Network of Schools in Partnership (NNSP) Annual Conference, 2001 October (Box 40, Folder 225)
    Grantee: The Aspen Institute, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 1997 April 01-2008 September 30
    Grant Number: 09700745
    Grant Purpose: Support for an evaluation of leading sectoral employment programs (950-1374)
    Grant Amount: $2,375,918.00; $2,375,918.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Colborn, John L.; McGahey, Richard
  - Ford Foundation Project PA 10200951 - Religion and Society: Meeting the Challenge of Pluralism, 2002-2003 (Box 40, Folder 226)
    Grantee: Douglas Gould Co, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 2002 July 01-2007 November 30
    Grant Number: 10200951
    Grant Purpose: To implement a communications strategy to increase the impact of the work of grantees in the foundation's Religion and Culture: Meeting the Challenge of Pluralism initiative
    Grant Amount: $1,627,500.00; $1,627,500.00
  - National Rural Development & Finance Corporation PA 09801793 - Montana Native American Development and Finance Initiative Annual Report, 1999 (Box 40, Folder 227)
    Grantee: Rural Development Finance Corporation
    Grant Dates: 09801793
    Grant Number: 1998 September 01-2004 April 30
    Grant Purpose: Prog of research, training, and technical assistance to build enterprise dev capacity among Native American organizations in Montana
    Grant Amount: $950,000.00; $950,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Owens, Millard A.
  - National Rural Development & Finance Corporation PA 09801793 - Montana Video, 1999 September 1; CD-R (Box 40)
    Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - International Association for the Evaluation of Educational Achievement PA 10000888, 1998-2000 (Box 40, Folder 228)
    Grantee: International Association for the Evaluation of Educational Achievement-The Netherlands (IEA)
    Grant Dates: 2000 January 01-2004 April 30
    Grant Number: 10000888
    Grant Purpose: Support for international comparative research on innovative classroom practice using technology
    Grant Amount: $650,000.00; $650,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Petrovich, Janice; Aguerrebere, Joseph; Driver, Cyrus; Balan, Jorge
  - Consumers International PA 10300289 - Decision Making in the Global Marketplace Modules 1&2, Interim Progress Report, 2004 (Box 40, Folder 229)
    Grantee: International Organization of Consumers Unions
    Grant Dates: 2003 January 01-2004 December 31
    Grant Number: 10300289
    Grant Purpose: For a review of accountability of three global governance regimes: the World Trade Organization, Codex Alementarius and the International Organization for Standardization
    Grant Amount: $268,300.00; $268,300.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Jordan, Lisa
  - Center for Community Change PA 10000983, 2001-2002 (Box 41, Folder 230)
    Grantee: Center for Community Change
    Grant Dates: 2008 August 01-2010 July 31
    Grant Number: 10000983
    Grant Purpose: Support for the national campaign for jobs and income support
    Ford Program Officer(s): Neuborne, Helen; McGahey, Richard; Colborn, John L.; Cordero-Guzman, Hector R.
  - The Foundation Center PA 10001093 - Fact Sheet, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 231)
    Grantee: The Foundation Center
    Grant Dates: 2000 January 01-2006 December 31
    Grant Number: 10001093
    Grant Purpose: General support to collect, organize, analyze, and disseminate information on foundation and corporate giving, and partial support for the relocation and construction of the washington, dc library
    Ford Program Officer(s): Harris, Christopher
  - The Rural School and Community Trust PA 10200998 - A Reasonably Equal Share: Education Equity in Vermont and Senate Bill 2488 Mississippi Legislature, 2000-2001 (Box 41, Folder 232)
  - Association for Research on Nonprofit Organizations and Voluntary Action (ARNOVA) PA 09800797 - Research Abstracts, Hotel Inter-Continental, New Orleans, LA, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 233)
    Grantee: Association for Research on Nonprofit Organizations and Voluntary Action
    Grant Dates: 1998 April 01-2011 March 31
    Grant Number: 09800797
    Grant Purpose: Support for technical assistance, electronic communications, and research dissemination activities
    Grant Amount: $754,500.00; $754,500.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Edwards, Michael; Jordan, Lisa
  - Southeast Asia Resource Action Center (SEARAC) PA 10350485, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 234)
    Grantee: Southeast Asia Resource Action Center
    Grant Dates: 2003 July 01-2005 June 30
    Grant Number: 10350485
    Grant Purpose: General support for policy analysis, advocacy and public education to advance the rights of Southeast Asian Americans and Southeast Asian refugees in the United States
  - National Partnership for Women & Families, Inc. PA 09800934, 1999-2004 (Box 41, Folder 235-236, Box 42, Folder 237-238)
  - Open Forum on Reproductive Health and Rights PA 09400291 - Informe Narrativo: Proyecto Institucional de Continuidad - 2003, Foro Red de Salud y Derechos Sexuales y Reproductivos, 1998-2004 (Box 42, Folder 239, Box 43, Folder 240-241)
    Grantee: Open Forum on Reproductive Health and Rights
    Grant Dates: 1994 March 01-2006 October 13
    Grant Number: 09400291
    Grant Purpose: Involvement of women's organizations in improvement of public reproductive health services
    Grant Amount: $1,385,650.00; $1,385,650.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Ore Aguilar, Gaby; Abreg, Martn
  - University of Notre Dame PA 10100797 - Center for Civil and Human Rights Transitional Justice Project, 2004-2007 (Box 43, Folder 242-243, Box 44, Folder 244)
    Grantee: The University of Notre Dame Du Lac
    Grant Dates: 2001 May 01-2004 April 30
    Grant Purpose: Support for the University's Center for Civil and Human Rights to establish an Accountability Resource Center and conduct related activities
  - Shanyama Consultancy Limited PA 10351700 - Ford Foundation 40th Anniversary of Kenya's Independence and Nairobi Office Pictures, 2003; CD-R (Box 44)
    Grantee: Shanyama Consultancy Limited
    Grant Dates: 2003 August 01-2005 April 30
    Grant Number: 10351700
    Grant Purpose: To coordinate and manage activities celebrating the joint 40th anniversary of Kenya's independence and Nairobi office grant making
    Ford Program Officer(s): Nuvunga, Milagre
  - Educational Forum, Concurso de Documentales Educativos PA 10251854, 2004 (Box 44, Folder 245)
    Grantee: Educational Forum
    Grant Dates: 2002 September 01-2003 December 31
    Grant Number: 10251854
    Grant Purpose: To administer a competitive fund for the production of five documentary films on education reform issues in Peru
    Grant Amount: $160,000.00; $160,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Palacios, Maria Amelia
  - Open Forum of Reproductive Health and Rights PA 09400291 - Convencion Nacional de Salud de las Mujeres, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 246)
  - Open Forum of Reproductive Health and Rights PA 09400291 - Campaa Internacional de Accin por la Salud de la Mujer, 1995 May 28; Audio CD (Box 44)
  - Prometra International PA 10701160 - Training of Traditional Healers Across in Africa on HIV Counseling and Stigma Reduction, and the Clinical Assessment of a Herbal Microbicidal Preparation - Reports, 2008 July; CD (Box 44)
    Grantee: Association for the Promotion of Traditional Medicine
    Grant Dates: 2007 August 01-2009 January 31
    Grant Number: 10701160
    Grant Purpose: For the training of traditional healers across Africa in HIV counseling and stigma reduction and the clinical assessment of a herbal microbicidal preparation
    Ford Program Officer(s): Ahonsi, Babatunde; Kamal, Montasser; Rios, Sara
  - National Board for Professional Teaching Standards (NBPTS) PA 10701225 Grant Product, 2009; CD (Box 44)
    Grantee: National Board for Professional Teaching Standards
    Grant Dates: 2007 July 01-2008 November 30
    Grant Number: 10701225
    Grant Purpose: For its Access and Equity initiative to make National Board Certification available and affordable to teachers in less affluent communities, especially in low-performing schools
    Grant Amount: $845,000.00; $845,000.00
  - Association of Citizens Advice Bureaus PA 09801523, 2000 (Box 44, Folder 247, Box 45, Folder 248-249, Box 46, Folder 250)
    Grantee: Association of Citizen Advice Bureaus
    Grant Dates: 1998 May 01-2004 September 30
    Grant Number: 09801523
    Grant Purpose: Support to promote public interest law in Eastern Europe
    Ford Program Officer(s): Grudzinska-Gross, Irena
  - Citizen Power Foundation PA 09600288 - Programa Accin Colectiva por la Justicia, Fundacin Poder Ciudadano y Fundacin Ford, 2002-2003 (Box 46, Folder 251-252)
    Grantee: Citizen Power Foundation
    Grant Dates: 1996 January 01-2008 October 31
    Grant Number: 09600288
    Grant Purpose: To promote accountability mechanisms and public interest issues
    Grant Amount: $1,476,000.00; $1,476,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Abreg, Martn; Varas, Augusto; Palacios, Maria Amelia; Lacoste, Jean Paul
  - Indonesian Musicological Society PA 08801093 - Laporan Tahunan Mspi (Annual Reports), 2000-2004 (Box 46, Folder 253)
    Grantee: Indonesian Society for Performing Arts
    Grant Dates: 1988 July 01-2005 June 30
    Grant Number: 08801093
    Grant Purpose: For the activities of a professional society devoted to the study of Indonesian performing arts
    Grant Amount: $1,096,000.00; $1,096,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Yampolsky, Philip
  - Foundation Carlos Chagas PA 08200450 - Relaes de Gnero na Sociedade Brasileira - Ill Programa de Incentivo e Formao em Pesquisa sobre Mulheres - Relatrio Anual, 1997-1998 (Box 47, Folder 254)
    Grantee: Carlos Chagas Foundation
    Grant Dates: 1982 March 30-2005 December 31
    Grant Number: 08200450
    Grant Purpose: Support for a national research competition in women's studies in Brazil
    Grant Amount: $1,775,350.00; $1,775,350.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Brooke, Nigel P.; Dora, Denise Dourado
  - El Colegio Mexiquense PA 10500309 - Anexos, 2005 (Box 47, Folder 255)
    Grantee: El Colegio Mexiquense
    Grant Dates: 2005 January 01-2011 February 28
    Grant Number: 10500309
    Grant Purpose: To strengthen an international network studying the interfaces between religion and the state and how they influence sexuality and reproductive health policies and programs
    Grant Amount: $1,070,000.00; $1,070,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Klugman, Barbara; Bronfman, Mario
  - Pontificia Universidad Catlica Del Per PA 09801086 - Departamento de Ciencias Sociales, Informe Narrativo "Sociedad Civil y Democracia en America Latina. Segunda Fase: Redes Sociales y Liderazgo Politico Local, Investigador Principal Dr. Aldo Panfichi, 2002-2004 (Box 47, Folder 256)
    Grantee: Pontifical Catholic University of Peru
    Grant Dates: 1998 May 01-2004 February 29
    Grant Number: 09801086
    Grant Purpose: Country and regional participation in a worldwide comparative research project on the relationship between civil society and governance
    Grant Amount: $351,000.00; $351,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Varas, Augusto
  - Association of Citizens Advice Bureaus PA 09801523 - Podrecznik Doradcy Podstawowe Umiejetnosci Doradcze, 2002-2003 (Box 47, Folder 257)
  - Association of Citizens Advice Bureaus PA 09801523 - Informator ZBPA, 2003 January 2; CD (Box 47)
  - Boston College PA 10201090, 2002-2003 (Box 47, Folder 258)
    Grantee: The Trustees of Boston College
    Grant Dates: 2002 September 01-2008 August 31
    Grant Number: 10201090
    Grant Purpose: To examine the effects of high-stakes testing and affirmative action policies on enrollment and graduation rates of minority and white students in secondary and postsecondary educational institutions
    Grant Amount: $750,000.00; $750,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Driver, Cyrus
  - Children's Action Alliance PA 10101629 - Make Kids Count: Giving Babies a Smart Beginning, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 259)
    Grantee: Childrens Action Alliance, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 2001 September 01-2004 August 31
    Grant Number: 10101629
    Grant Purpose: For activities to increase state commitment to working poor families in Arizona
    Grant Amount: $300,000.00; $300,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Sconyers, Nancy
  - Municipio de Concordia 09600413 - Anexo Nro. 1 Fotographs, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 260)
    Grantee: Codesarrollo Foundation
    Grant Dates: 1996 January 01-2002 June 30
    Grant Number: 09600413
    Grant Purpose: Support for education and community economic development programs in rural areas of Antioquia
    Grant Amount: $215,000.00; $215,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Tillett, Anthony D.
  - Asia Society (09900817), 2002 (Box 48, Folder 261)
    Grantee: Asia Society
    Grant Dates: 1999 July 01-2005 June 30
    Grant Number: 09900817
    Grant Purpose: Support for an endowment for a new initiative to educate Americans about Asian social-policy issues and innovations
    Ford Program Officer(s): Rizvi, S. A. Gowher
  - Foundation-Administered Project (10190003), 2000-2005 (Box 48, Folder 262)
  - Foundation-Administered Project - New Media Publishing (10190003), 2002 (Box 48, Folder 263)
  - Foundation-Administered Project - APEX (10190003), 2002 (Box 48, Folder 264)
  - Appleseed Foundation, Inc. (10450144), 2003-2004 (Box 48, Folder 265)
    Grantee: Appleseed Foundation, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 2004 January 01-2005 June 30
    Grant Number: 10450144
    Grant Purpose: For research and other activities to encourage greater small business support of low-wage workers in Alabama, Nebraska, South Carolina, and New Jersey
    Grant Amount: $150,000.00; $150,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Neuborne, Helen
  - National Council for Community and Education Partnerships - Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs (GEAR UP) (10001544), 1998-2000 (Box 49, Folder 266-267)
    Grantee: National Council on Community and Education Partnerships (NCCEP) (10001544),
    Grant Dates: 1999 October 01-2004 February 29
    Grant Number: 10001544
    Grant Purpose: To manage and provide technical assistance to the department of education's gaining early awareness and readiness for undergraduate programs (GEAR UP)
    Grant Amount: $2,692,500.00; $2,692,500.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Zwerling, L. Steven
  - U.S. Committee for Refugees and Immigrants, Inc. (10100170) Immigration and Refugee Services of America Publications, 2000-2002 (Box 49, Folder 268, Box 50, Folder 269)
    Grantee: U.S. Committee for Refugees and Immigrants, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 2001 October 01-2005 September 3
    Grant Number: 10100170
    Grant Purpose: Support for public information and advocacy on international refugee issues
    Grant Amount: $1,300,000.00; $1,300,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Higashi, Taryn; Aidoo, Akwasi; Gitari, Joseph
  - Rand Corporation (10251826), 2001-2002 (Box 50, Folder 270)
    Grantee: Rand Corporation
    Grant Dates: 2002 October 01-2005 March 31
    Grant Number: 10251826
    Grant Purpose: To evaluate the effects of state-based education reform efforts to improve student achievement
    Ford Program Officer(s): Aguerrebere, Joseph; Petrovich, Janice; Driver, Cyrus
  - Foundation-Administered Project - Capital Business Systems (10190003), 2002 (Box 50, Folder 271)
  - The University of the West Indies (09101394) - Institute of Social and Economic Studies (ISER), 1986-1988 (Box 50, Folder 272)
    Grantee: The University of the West Indies
    Grant Dates: 1992 September 01-2002 August 31
    Grant Number: 09101394
    Grant Purpose: Support for a university endowment campaign
    Grant Amount: $915,000.00; $915,000.00
  - Pontifical Catholic University of Peru (09801086), 1998-1999 (Box 50, Folder 273, Box 51, Folder 274-275)
  - Educational Forum (10251671), 2002-2003 (Box 51, Folder 276-277, Box 52, Folder 278-279)
    Grant Dates: 2002 July 01-2004 July 31
    Grant Number: 10251671
    Grant Purpose: To establish civil society education task forces in four regions of Peru to conduct public dialogues and foster consensus building on and collective participation in education decentralization
    Grant Amount: $275,000.00; $275,000.00